like well you've brought your Raspberry
就像你带来了你的树莓一样
Pi yeah we have shown Raspberry Pi
Pi是的，我们已经展示了Raspberry Pi
builds on the show in the past okay so
那么在过去的展会上建立起来就好了
so where our viewers are reasonably
所以我们的观众是合理的
familiar what can I that some of them
熟悉我能说他们中的一些
have even gone out and bought one we
甚至出去买了一个我们
sell them through our website cat5 TV /
通过我们的网站cat5 TV /
pie you've got yours tell you about you
馅饼你有你告诉你
know what yes I brought my baby here
知道我在这里带我的宝贝是什么
today guys and I'm really excited to
今天我们都很兴奋
show you because it's the new Raspberry
告诉你，因为它是新的树莓
Pi the third version else so like the
Pi的第三个版本，所以喜欢它
new three-point a raspberry pi 3 it's
新的三点树莓pi 3它
it's my baby right now guys I got for
这是我的宝贝，现在我得到的人
Christmas I came with a kit and of
圣诞节我带着 一个工具包和
course like Robbie just said you go
罗比只是说你走了
online to their store and you can look
在线到他们的商店，你可以看看
at what they have online there so did
他们在网上也是这样
you get like this breadboard and
你会喜欢这个面包板和
everything yeah you know what I I got
一切都是你知道我得到了什么
exactly this and it's really cool
正是这个，这真的 很酷
because um obviously now it has a four
因为很明显现在它有四个
core processor yeah which is absolutely
核心处理器是绝对的
fantastic it has Wi-Fi Bluetooth and of
太棒了，它有Wi-Fi蓝牙和
course it comes with its own operating
当然它有它自己的操作
system to like it has raspbian installed
系统喜欢它已安装raspbian
which is kind of like a linux version
这有点像Linux版本
smoosh generation habian yeah okay which
smoosh一代habian耶没关系哪个
is yeah and you know what I've had so
是啊，你知道我有这样的
much fun and the best part is is that
很有趣， 最好的部分是
it's made for everyone it doesn't matter
这是为所有人做的，无所谓
if you're a six-year-old just getting
如果你是一个六岁刚刚获得
into computers wanting to have fun or if
到电脑想要玩得开心或如果
you're a Robbie who knows his way around
你是罗比谁知道在他的方式
computers um but you know what yes i am
电脑，但你知道我是什么
that i am that Robbie you what I am that
我是罗比你我是那样的
I your body however yes this to me
但是我的身体对我来说是这样的
introduces new skills new hobbies new
引入新技能新爱好新
experimentation and fun oh yeah I've
实验和乐趣哦，是的，我已经
mentioned that on the show you know
在节目上提到你知道
we're trying to get more into hands-on
我们正在尝试更多的动手
let's learn to do this let's actually
让我们学习如何做到这一点吧
build this and do this exactly that's
建立这一点，并做到这一点
what the pie represents to me is the
什么派代表到我是
ability to very cheaply be able to start
能够非常便宜地启动
tinkering and start learning on
修补并开始学习
electronics start learning some of these
电子开始学习其中的一些
really really neat things that you can
真的很干净你可以做的事情
do exactly and the really really amazing
做完全和真的 很神奇
part about a pie is that a they're
关于一个馅饼的部分是他们
inexpensive but as well as the more
价格便宜，但还有更多的
important part you set rate their hands
你设定的重要部分评价他们的手
on yeah you know we can actually build
是的，你知道我们可以建立
things you can actually do your own
事实上你可以做你自己的事情
projects and there's pretty
项目，还有漂亮的
unlimited potential like you get it you
无限的潜力就像你得到它
could get like an LCD screen with it
可以像它的液晶屏幕一样
should we get up sure you can turn it
我们应该确保你可以把它打开
into a little low you could do anything
变得有点低，你可以做任何事情
with these things you know and the cool
这些 东西你 知道，很酷
thing is is that you can also work on
事情是，你也可以继续努力
the programming side too because it
编程方面也是因为它
comes pre-loaded nowadays with all this
所有这些都是现在预装的
amazing free software from all skill
来自所有技能的惊人免费软件
levels so obviously like you have Python
水平如此明显，就像你有Python一样
you have JavaScript things like that but
你有这样的JavaScript的东西，但
you also have other smaller free
你也有其他更小的自由
programs that can start like videos like
可以像视频一样开始的节目
coding languages exactly on the pie yeah
编码语言完全在饼是啊
and is Linux exactly it has these what
而Linux正是它有这些
are called gpio headers and what they do
被称为gpio标题和他们做什么
is they allow you to connect and I see
他们是否允许你连接，我看到了
you've got here I'll via those
你已经到了我会通过这些
connectors there it looks like an old
它看起来像一个旧的连接器
ide kind of thing yep what is that what
这种事情是什么，那是什么
capabilities does that give us an
功能确实给了我们一个
unlimited power no that really cool i'll
无限的力量没有那么酷我会
know about that it really does give us
知道它确实给了我们
so much potential though because well
尽管如此，潜力很大
we're able to plug in switches lights
我们可以插入开关灯
yeah these other amazing things and with
是的，这些其他惊人的事情和
that you can do the most simple projects
你 可以做最简单的项目
for example i made like a little
例如我做了一点点
stoplight there it's not working what i
红绿灯有它不工作我
thought was right now yeah you pushing
现在想你是在推动你
this which okay here let me let me get
这里面 还好这里让我，让我得到
in here can you tell us a little bit
在这里你能告诉我们一点点
about this particular built so you're
关于这个特别的建立，所以你
pulling more than just power here yeah
这里拉动的不仅仅是力量呀
so how it works is that generally right
所以它的工作原理通常是正确的
now you see three LEDs so you have your
现在你看到三个LED，所以你有你的
red here yellow and of course green and
这里的红色是黄色的，当然是绿色的
then of course you haven't switch over
那当然你还没有转过身
here okay so on it's not working quite
这里没关系，所以它没有工作
right now but when you push the switch
现在，但是当你按下开关时
its supposed to switch in between and
它应该在和之间切换
why is it not is this I accidentally
为什么这不是我意外的呢？
forgot a resistor at home but yeah I
在家里忘了一个电阻，但是我是
want to get to that point where I just
想要达到那一点，我只是
have resistors in my pocket and I can
我的口袋里有电阻，我可以
just hand one to you you should because
只是给你一个你应该因为
that would be so much fun I'll be like a
这将是非常有趣的，我会像一个
Robbie's here to save the day this looks
罗比在这里拯救了这一天
like a lot of fun how much technical
喜欢很多有趣的技术
knowledge like one of the things like I
知识就像我之类的事情
don't I don't really get my I don't have
我不是真的没有我的我没有
my head around resistors yet yeah I can
我的头在电阻周围，但我可以
understand relays and I've built a nice
了解中继，我已经建立了一个很好的
little relay system which we're going to
我们要去的小中继系统
be looking at on a future episode that's
在看对未来的插曲这
going to be fun and yeah but I resistors
会很有趣， 是的，但我的电阻
and things like that like how how much
和像这样的事情有多么多
knowledge do you have to have in order
你需要掌握的知识
to start building they're really not at
开始建设他们真的不在
all literally this is my first time
所有字面上这 是我第一次
really building
真的建设
from scratch like this and that's a
像这样从头开始，这是一个
really amazing part is that there's two
真正了不起的部分是有两个
categories of course the internet it's a
当然互联网的类别是一个
wonderful place a lot of free knowledge
精彩的地方有很多免费的知识
out there watch category 5 because they
在那里观看类别5，因为他们
talk about pie a lot I'm Paul Morphy
谈论馅饼很多 我是Paul Morphy
blog while your dad I think no but it's
博客，而你的爸爸，我认为不，但它是
um again you can get packages online
再次，你可以在网上获得包裹
again look through your store because
再次浏览你的商店，因为
there's so many amazing resources like
有这么多惊人的资源
for example mine came with a little book
比如我的小书
that gave you example projects and I'm
那给了你示例项目和我
gonna go show shows you have
要去演出你有
step-by-step how to actually build in
一步一步如何真正建立
and explains everything right so if we
并解释一切，如果我们
can actually like show them the actual
实际上可以 让他们看到实际情况
like Python program that's running this
就像运行这个的Python程序一样
right now they would actually be able to
现在他们实际上能够 做到
see the code and there's actually a
看代码，实际上 有一个
program that's running this stoplight
运行此红灯的程序
yeah it there's an actual code written
是的，它有一个实际的代码写的
in Python yeah it's running that stopped
在Python是啊，它 停止 运行
like you see how that works or yes we
就像你看到那是如何工作的，或者是我们
can okay we actually have ready on the
可以，我们实际上已经准备好了
pie nice um so as you can see you guys
馅饼很好，所以你可以看到你们
this is the desktop of my pie which is
这是我的派的桌面
absolutely amazing i love it there you
绝对令人惊叹，我喜欢它那里你
go get very low resolution like it's
像这样得到非常低的分辨率
built for the little touch screen or
专为小触摸屏或者
something like it see that that's that's
就像它看到的那样
a cool thing goes that's still very
一件很酷的事情依然如此
adaptable yeah right and the amount of
适应性是正确的和金额
power that you have in it can be
你拥有的力量可以
overkill but the thing is that you can
矫枉过正，但事情是， 你可以
literally do anything can make like a
从字面上做任何事情都可以做成像
little Wi-Fi router you can make a media
小的Wi-Fi路由器可以制作媒体
server off this yeah we've done a plex
服务器关闭这是我们做了一个丛
media server hey there you go do a
媒体服务器嘿，你去做一个
search on our website category five TV
在我们的网站上搜索五类电视
do a search for raspberry pi and see all
做一个搜索覆盆子pi和看到所有
the things that we've done oh yeah but
但是 ，我们所做的事情噢
so I see a lot of script there so this
所以我在这里看到很多脚本
runs that traffic light is this look at
运行该交通灯是这样看的
that led on off yeah like we got the
那就像是我们得到的那样
GPIO of those pin designations yep and
这些引脚名称的GPIO是和
then and that's a really amazing thing
那么这真是一件了不起的事情
about the education when it comes to pi
关于pi的教育
is that you have something that is
是，你有什么事情 是
really simple but you have all these
真的很简单，但你拥有所有这些
amazing online projects I can it breaks
令人惊叹的在线项目我可以打破
you down step by step okay right and
你一步一步好的权利和
you're able to go through that and
你可以去 通过 和
there's so many great online resources
有这么多伟大的在线资源
heck even on reddit you just answered
甚至在你刚刚回答的reddit上
Raspberry Pi and is that it you just
树莓派，就是你
kind of do a search for hey some
有些人会为此寻找嘿
beginner projects for all this berry pie
所有这个浆果派的初学者项目
or yeah exactly a killer resource that
或者是一个真正的杀手资源
we should be looking at
我们应该看看
there's quite a few um so there's
有很多这样的
obviously books check your library
显然书籍检查你的图书馆
things like that really they have
像他们真的有这样的事情
raspberry pi project books oh yeah a lot
覆盆子pi项目书哦很多
a lot of libraries are keeping up at the
很多图书馆都在跟上
times are really amazing how they have
时间真的很惊人，他们有
so many amazing resources for kids
这么多惊人的资源给孩子们
nowadays um and especially for adults
现在呢，特别是成年人
you know what Kiptyn get to the hard
你知道Kiptyn的难处
side us you know it's funny because some
在我们身边你知道这很 有趣，因为有些
of the things that I got for Christmas
我在圣诞节得到的东西
because I'm trying to learn these kinds
因为我正在努力学习这些
of things electronics and how how it
电子产品的事情以及如何如何
actually works really at its core say
实际上它的核心意义是真正的
for ages 6 and up or ages 8 not and it's
对于6岁以上或8岁不是，这是
you know that we if we don't have that
你知道我们，如果我们没有那个
knowledge no it's for me well it's it's
知识没有它对我来说就是这样
crazy though because the only thing you
疯狂的，但因为你 的 唯一 的 事情
look at kids nowadays though and you see
现在看看孩子们，你看
a four-year-old who knows more about an
一个四岁的孩子更了解一个孩子
iphone so a lot of other people out
iphone等很多其他人出来
there but take it apart they don't know
但是要把它分开，他们不知道
necessarily what no there's having
一定不会有什么
splashy this things yeah and again
这 件事情一次又一次地 浮现 出来
that's this is where a project like this
这就是这样一个项目的地方
can come in handy right early you use
可以在你使用的早期派上用场
your hands right so I think it's a great
你的手对，所以我认为这是一个伟大的
education tool and I mean like I'm so
教育工具，我的意思就像我是如此
excited for the next decade I'm sorry
对未来十年感到非常抱歉
yeah huge Artemis yeah and and not and
是啊，巨大的阿耳忒弥斯是啊，而不是和
we we talk about education we're not
我们谈论我们不是的教育
just talking about rules like I guess be
只是谈论像我想的那样的规则
doing these kinds of projects with my
和我一起做这些项目
kids exact really see it and with the
孩子确切地看到它和与
breadboard what's cool about that too is
面包板有什么好处呢
that you're not permanently soldering
你不是永久焊接的
this thing together that is something
这件事情在一起就是事情
that you know you're able to pull it
你知道你可以拉它
apart and build the next one exactly you
分开，并建立下一个恰好你
can do a project you want to try it all
可以做一个项目，你想尝试 一切
over again okay it's just ripped apart
好了，它只是被撕开了
and start over and that's the cool thing
并重新开始，这是很酷的事情
is that again you can make sure it works
这是你可以确保它的工作
before you solder everything and you
在焊接一切和你之前
can't take it right okay and then you
不能把事情做好，然后你
give you the money a TCP so where do you
给你一个TCP的钱，你在哪里
get the parts i mean you can get them
得到的部分我的意思是你可以得到它们
through our affiliate link our partner
通过我们的会员链接我们的合作伙伴
link for amazon yeah exactly and Barrie
链接亚马逊耶和 巴里完全一样
Ontario we are absolutely blessed to
安大略省，我们非常幸运
have a store called say al and say al is
有一个叫al的商店，并说al是
like the radio shack of old like you
就像你一样的老式收音机小屋
gonna do row after row of resistors and
会排成一排排电阻和
relays and everything else it is
继电器和其他一切
paradise for a tinkerer but you know
一个修仙者的天堂，但你知道
where would you buy Part D is that what
你会在哪里购买D部分是什么
you do here yeah yeah you know what on a
你在这里做是的，你知道你在做什么
lot of local tech stores have amazing
很多当地的高科技商店都很棒
parts yeah um I also look at like I said
部分是啊，我也看起来像我说的
before a lot of kits because
之前很多工具包因为
um again they might have things cater
再次，他们可能有东西迎合
towards so like example there might be
朝着这样的例子可能会有
like seven different projects like I
像我这样的七个不同的项目
heard somebody in the chat will saw a
听到有人在聊天中会看到 一个
not hurt I'm talking about like the
没有伤害我正在谈论像
magic mirror idea how project yeah they
魔镜的想法如何项目耶他们
caked in here thank you very much for
在这里 结块 非常感谢你
mentoring that vitally on how you take a
指导你如何采取行动
mirror and then you make it a smart
镜子，然后让它变得聪明
meter so it's like the time the weather
所以它就像天气的时间
things like that um and they're i'm
像这样的事情，他们就是我
pretty sure they're should week it's out
非常确定他们应该在周内出局
there that can i'm surprised mr. war if
在那里，我可以很惊讶先生。战争如果
there aren't kids out there somebody
有人没有孩子
make a kit because that would sell very
做一个工具包，因为那会卖得很
fast or it might be fun to actually
快或者它实际上可能很有趣
that's out the head yeah head on over to
这是头脑耶
our website category five dot TV and you
我们的网站类别五 点电视 和你
can actually click on our support us and
实际上可以点击我们的支持我们和
then our partner links through our
那么我们的合作伙伴链接通过我们
partner links amazon is a great resource
合作伙伴链接亚马逊是一个很好的资源
for these kinds of poland really i think
对于这些波兰我真的觉得
up something diff so many and kit like
不同的东西差不多和工具包一样
do a search for kit for raspberry pi
做一个搜索覆盆子pi的工具包
it's amazing but also if you want to buy
它是惊人的， 但如果你想购买
a pie if you haven't got yours yet cat5
如果你还没有你的猫，那么就是一个馅饼5
TV / pies we've got a lot of accessories
电视/ 馅饼我们有很多配件
we've got the kits themselves to get you
我们有自己的工具包来帮助你
started and then as we evolve these
开始，然后当我们 发展这些
kinds of projects on the show will be
展会上将有各种项目
able to you'll be able to follow along
能够让你能够跟随
with those kits as well so it's going to
与那些包，以及因此它 要
be a lot of fun thanks for bringing that
有很多 乐趣感谢 为使 这一
in henry and make driving it that's a
在亨利，并驾驶它是一个
lot of fun very cool
很多乐趣很酷
[Music]
[音乐]